I'm joined today by Heather and possibly
another person if they if they show up
this week's question is how are you
feeling about the world right now
looking forward to hearing the idea cafe
is going is a space and will eventually
be its own platform where everybody gets
to show up exactly as they are and have
a conversation with real people in real
time to connect humanity in a way that
our current social media platforms
definitely don't and i'm also envision
@vn a social media platform that we all
own together and operate together so
that as we all see ways to improve it so
that it's a more enjoyable conversation
or a more productive conversation we can
we can add those features so that we can
get started so like I said this week's
question is how are you feeling about
the world right now and as people share
people there's only two of us as we eat
sure I've been dropping down likewhen
tea session when I was five of us so
that just the person's face is on camera
to share and you know you kind of have
the spotlight for that time period yeah
that is what yeah we didn't do that the
first week and it works kind of there's
pros and cons to both ways both ways of
doing it so I'll suggest would you like
to start sharing Heather would you like
me to start why don't you start okay all
right so I'll just drop you down and
then I'll try to keep my eye on the
5-minute marker and then I'll sure all
right how I am feeling about the world
right now is a very dichotomous very
divided I feel that the track we are on
that humanity is living towards is chaos
and it makes me feel uneasy and sad and
very worried about our future and at the
same time this week especially there are
millions of people marching in the
street demanding our governments take
action on climate change and even if I
don't think that is the course of action
that we is the most effective I still
very much appreciate that there are so
many people out there who care who are
showing up and and sharing that they
want a better world I have a lot of hope
for the future I got introduced to game
B over the last couple weeks and with
game became an introduction to a lot of
humans who also care about the world and
also want a new system rather than the
one we're currently playing game a is
what we're currently playing that is
very leading us sports collapse but is
very its combative there's winners and
losers and so the idea is game B has to
come out of game a and it also is a
system that should be on the wind that
should be everybody wins and what I have
envisioned over the last three years for
a global cooperative I think gets us
there so I've had been sitting in this
weird feeling of I have hope for the
future because I have a real idea that
can get us there and at the same time
feeling constantly like how can I be the
one to get us there with my limitations
and my who I am and so I've had to do a
lot of personal development a lot of
meditation and and growth and learning
through just making mistakes and
figuring it out and I have every belief
that we can create a better world
together just why I keep showing up who
I keep putting myself online the idea
Cafe is the newest iteration of that I
have so much I can see where this can go
having a space that all of humanity can
come to be part of a conversation when
we are not divided like we currently are
when you can't just have your side or
another side yelling at the other groups
you know telling you what you believe
until I'm not listening say listening to
what people believe it actually
listening for understanding I this last
week have had visions of creating
citizens assembly which is what the
extinction rebellion wants to do they
want our governments to do it so that we
can
so that their governments listened to
the citizens assembly and isn't this
bipartisan every four years of
fluctuates back and forth and I see very
much that our idea Cafe platform that I
envision can be used to just pull the
citizens assembly now and can meet the
first two demands which are tell the
truth and take action that we can do
that and so I am excited to actually be
doing this every week this week was a
little hard because there aren't the
same number of people that are working
here last week but also I didn't put in
the same effort I did last week I didn't
reach out to people until Monday because
I was busy doing game B stuff and
thinking about that so that that's my
learning this week is how to how to grow
this and how to make this a space of
inclusion and enjoyment that people want
to come to and want to share in the
moment and I know YouTube is a weird
space to do it on because it's not zoom
it's not private it's it's showing up
and going live in front of the world my
15 subscribers but theoretically it
could be and so I want a platform that
everybody feels the safe and comfortable
on because I want everybody to be able
to show up not just people who are
comfortable being on camera on YouTube
so that is how I'm feeling about the
world right now
and that is is definitely my my five
minutes so welcome back Heather thank
you I will drop my seats down and you
can share when you're when you're ready
you don't have to take okay well thank
you for sharing all of that and I can
pick up a lot of threads from that in my
own experience which is what I want to
do but rather than do that I'm gonna I'm
gonna come to the present moment and
address the question which is how do I
feel about the world right now hmm and
my temptation is always to go to what I
think about the world but what I feel
about the world is
I think I'm gonna use your word of
dichotomy but I feel sadness and
excitement I feel loss and potential I
feel death and burst now the sad side
the death side the sense of something
coming to an end game a feels more
certain to me and the potential side the
rebirth side feels tenuous and unsure to
me and I think over arching all of that
is a real hope that that positive side
is picking up steam is starting to
coalesce into something that that could
gain the solidity that I sense in the
decline side of things and I feel that
being here this is a tiny it's a tiny
little rock dropped in the pond right
two people having this there's two
strangers having this small public
interface which is different than the
ways we're used to interacting and which
we're both approaching and I think a
very personal meaningful infinite game
way and that I see more of these small
efforts happening and it gives me a
sense that
that there's possibility for a sort of
non linear convergence emergence thing
starting to happen but at the same time
I also feel like the sadness is
important to feel and address and I I
think most of us have enough
difficulties in our life that that's
hard to do because it's a at this point
it's a voluntary thing that feeling into
sadness about the larger world is not
something that most people are resourced
for right now and I'm sort of working
towards that my my little thing right
now is what you were talking about about
self work and really trying to get to
the point where I feel like the
decisions I make in the wider world are
going to be helpful because right now
I'm not sure that they are so yeah and I
forgot to watch a clock but I'm gonna
call five minutes it may be less and
maybe more you don't have to talk for
five minutes five minutes is all or four
Wynnum there are four or five of us we
want to edit down so within half an hour
we want a few minutes at the end to talk
about how how that felt thank you so
much for sharing that
I felt like yours was much more succinct
to actually answer the question which is
how you're feeling I exist in a very
cognitive brain worlds which is where my
ideas have come from but have been
living more in a heart centered feeling
the emotion doing learning from the
emotions that come up learning from my
triggers and there's so much power there
and so much like that is how we change
the world like you said the feeling the
sadness is so important and I hope this
becomes a space that's where I like I
don't want it to be fake positivity by
any stretch like I want it to be real
and the irony that it's live on YouTube
like it's it's a ho
showing up and I'm envisioning ways of
bringing it off YouTube on to zoom and
into a space where anyone can show up to
discuss issues right be with each other
in that sadness and passion and vision
and confusion and the food is it's like
chaotic a chaotic time period and so
many people don't have community don't
have a space to do that in but they want
to and if we can create that for the
people who want to I think it's then
safer for the people who aren't quite
ready yet and so that's a bit of what I
got Thank You sherry that was that's the
idea we come back together feel like I'm
all over the place today it's like I'm
just trying to think cuz I've lost I've
lost my throat a little bit but so oh I
know what it was what's something that
you said that well if you think he said
that really landed but one of them was
coming out of this sort of cognitive
dominance space intellect dominant space
and that's very much where I come from
also and I'm on a a very new and strange
journey into feeling and being and
femininity all these things that are
that are you know not the sanctioned
order of our society and I've often feel
hope because precisely because I have
come from so far in the other direction
that if I can make this shift like
there's there were so many people that
are in a much more moderate place than I
ever was in terms of the balance between
emotion and intellect but hypothetically
it should be easier for them to to come
to a more heart centered place so it's
interesting you also came from that that
direction yeah it's funny I keep saying
because I think I've been putting my
idea out there for years now in in
various formats and I
wanting to explain it should like
convince you of the way right it to be
like but this is why and how and my
brain has a DD and recently I figured
out I also have autism and I also have
had brain tumors I have some brain
damage in between all of that and just
my personality and the way the world
works
the how and why it's never gonna bring
people the why is but the how and the
what doesn't bring people and even
though I'm like look at the spreadsheet
in the graphs where is speaking from my
heart and like my heart doesn't have a
DD like my heart and I love that my
brain does it's how I've been able to
think about it I don't want to discount
my brain for that but I'm like oh and I
speak from the heart and feel it feel it
speaking for my heart and like in my
throat it's much more emotion ends up
coming up
but people hear it better and resonate
with it more because they feel it in
their body they feel that hope or
sadness or whatever it is that's there
and but it's learning it's learning how
to do that how to tap into that more
especially when our world is very
cognitive and also that is like a right
or wrong thing it's like you know me I
can be proven wrong and like I've done
the work you can't prove me wrong right
like I can have the debate I can win it
I can it's like emotion isn't that it's
like you show up as you are and there's
no wrong to be you might do something
wrong in that emotion but you can't be
wrong for being angry or hopeful or sad
or feeling confused and so confusion is
one of the spaces I think we need to
confusion and shame are like to allow
people to be like that doesn't make
sense to me I'm comfortable enough and
my intellect to always say that what
what are you talking about I don't
understand what you're talking about
except in the hard space where I'm like
I don't know what I feel I don't know
what what is there and so yeah it's been
nice sitting with you and sharing that
that that it's not discomfort with
ambiguity right that we I guess because
the intellect doesn't want to allow for
ambiguity and we're so intellectual in
our culture
we've lost which is hilarious because
everything in life pretty much is
ambiguous and everything is uncertain
and to imagine that we're somehow can be
certain and that things cannot be
ambiguous is possibly the the least the
least close to reality that we could get
and yet when we're in that space it
feels completely true but it's
interesting it's yeah and it's a it's a
trip absolutely I mean my vision for a
global tech cooperative is a lot of
cognitive stuff is a lot of like how we
get on the same page on a lot of the
science stuff in history and not that it
has to be black and white there's a lot
of gray area and everything but like get
that down like a look at that see where
you know why we believe this and why we
believe that but part of that in order
to great create that in the world I've
had to get more heart-centered and
getting more heart center to felt the
more power in there and like it's like
almost like I want the cognitive piece
or just the online where we can all look
at it so we can all do the hard work so
like that's kind of done we have that if
you want to work on that you can but
also we don't need to because this is
where like the magic happens in
community and relationships and personal
growth is in the like emotions and
heart-centered and we all have different
things that interest us cognitively
whereas we all kind of experience the
same emotions and you know having more
tools to deal with our emotional
intelligence and how to sit with one
another in those uncomfortable emotions
is what we need in order to ask people
to join us in those uncomfortable
emotions right is like well what do you
do what do you like nothing is easier
than sitting meditating and nothing's
harder sitting with yourself in that
space is both like it feels like you're
gonna die a little bit and also like
it's only
Oshin and only thoughts that as far as I
know can't kill you and just a trip
every time that I you know re re get to
that yeah true I wonder when when you're
talking about having the the cognitive
stuff laid out and and then sort of the
heart stuff do you think the is the
cognitive stuff to you is that sort of
the what of the project and then the
heart is sort of the how or the why do
you divide it that way at all because
I've sort of found that delineation
happening for me
where society generally is all about
what what are we gonna do about climate
change what are we gonna do about this
what are we gonna do about that
important questions but the how the why
those things are I think associated with
the heart but I'm just curious if that
lands for you at all a little bit yeah
with at least for me putting the project
out there that's like I said definitely
been the case but I also feel like the
cognitive piece is to me truth-seeking
it's like whether I want this to be true
or not what is the actual truth what is
the data and what is the like where can
it go wrong and how like looking for the
reality even if it's not comfortable and
then on top of that maybe making it work
be like you know and we're allowed to
feel any way we do about that right that
like here is where carbons coming from
so you can't spin it you can't you know
the are your cultural industry you can't
point to the airplanes and the airplanes
point to a agricultural industry like
having actual truths and like how do we
know that and maybe we can never know
that but what's our best guess and where
does that come from so that we can then
deal with like the emotions of our
planet any how we actually like move
forward as a planet and so yeah I do
find those what how and that's every
time I sit down to explain something
those are literal I do all of the
questions like what when where why even
if they're not appropriate like yeah
that's how it makes it easier and the
why definitely brings out the emotional
side
and the how is both cognitive and
emotional because it's both
we need the we need the truth and we
need the the action the passion you know
the the to meet people where they are
that's a big piece is instead of
demanding you know because cognitively
I'm not vegan but I might be able to
convince you to go vegan cognitively but
it's never gonna convince you it's never
gonna get there whereas if like I can
ask you hey do you think we should all
eat more vegetarian if you do why aren't
you and how do we solve that together
instead of like you're wrong for eating
that way whatever way Pete and more
meeting people where they're at because
I don't have a solution to make people
not be who they are
I think the best growth happens when
we're seen and accepted for who we are
and then we can see where there's a
problem be like oh I'm gonna grow here
and I'm gonna grow there that makes that
makes a lot of sense the only thing that
hit me was I was really interesting and
I'm actually getting curious about more
about your background - like if you're
in academia or what what your history is
but I'm an artist and art is a way of
seeking subjective truth but it's not to
me it's not farther away from the truth
it's just a different path to it and one
of the things I'll point you to that's
so interesting is Van Gogh's Starry
Night I don't know if you're familiar
with the painting it's yeah the swirls
and the sky and everything so apparently
that's one of the best representations
of turbulence which is notoriously hard
to pin down visually what turbulent
looks like and so they like and it makes
sense like if I think about it to be
able to tune in to what does turbulence
feel like and somehow paint it there's a
very hard thing to do but it's possible
because because that feeling heart
intuition
have some kind of interface with with
everything around us and so it's also
capable of true perception it's just
it's just filtered up to us differently
hmm
yeah yeah I love that and I think that
my background is in academia I'm a
scientist by by trade and my other
Bachelor of Science and I think that is
like I think people somewhat fall on one
or the other but it's the inter woven
it's like how you know I love that I
don't know that a little story night and
having that be the like that's how and
when you look at nature and it's fractal
and it's like oh this is we try to
understand something and we always fail
as humans because we can't see the hole
we break the hole into parts that we
understand the parts and we think we can
put them back together and understand
the whole and we can't and I think art
helps hugely with that I know for me I'm
not I don't consider myself an artist
but where my best ideas have come from
was when I wasn't able to reap it in new
knowledge for other people because of my
brain changing I had to allow new things
to come new things our art like you
don't I mean like that is creating and
that's where the magic happens that's
where innovation happens where you know
science meets our needs meets it and so
yeah thank you and I love that you're
coming from science because I'm coming
from art fascinated by science so there
is a real yeah there's something so
there's something something so huge to
be gained I think when those
perspectives interweave it is just it
comes back to the original question it
gives me hope because as a culture we've
been really hitting the science hard for
a long time and to be able to interweave
that with the heart the embodied sense
the emotion the art I think
is hopeful if we can do that yeah yeah
and meet people where they're at cuz
some people aren't ready for the heart
space I was a intellectual for a reason
covered up something that I wasn't ready
to go into and I'm sure the other way
too if your intellectual and you feel
like you're not smart or sorry art you
know heart bass and you feel like you're
not smart enough to get the intellectual
part you haven't been told that you can
it's not okay to admit you don't know
something and that's where that yeah
like those two inch or whooping is like
meeting people where they are and figure
out how to help them and relieve it
which I think again is loving the more
there at making space for yeah for
everyone because they can yeah because
there's a there's a broader tapestry
once once there's a picture of a broader
tapestry not everyone has to fractal the
tapestry right that people can still be
at their poles if that's where they need
to be which I can relate that's where I
was for a lot most of my life but the
whole is a tapestry that many of the
parts can see that everyone can fit I
think yeah well no and that's to me like
I can see how everything in my life led
up to this point like every interest
every interaction everything for me to
do what I need to do to create a better
world and I'm losing my train of thought
as to what I was talking about in that
moment but the tapestry it like everyone
it's not about there's this idea that
diversity almost has to be demanded
right like all spaces have to be
inclusive spaces and like I don't think
you see what we get with diversity and
if you're demanding people see it we're
not getting really seen with diversity
like it's that we're all different we
all have different for different threads
in the tapestry yet we're all kind of
yelling at each other to be our thread
or to not be the thread like it's just a
weird you know we're in competition with
other threads it's like no we're making
up the hole and it involves finding that
way to weave us together and that's
gonna involve right left-brain feminine
masculine all of the binaries that are
starting to not be by it is that yeah
needs to
unfold and allowing people to be in the
confusion and shame and sad medicine
like be present with other people and
giving them the tools for that we're
almost at the half an hour mark I'm
gonna let you finish up anything you
want to say if there is anything and
then we can stop the going live and then
I'll say goodbye to you okay well my
heart feels very open right now I feel
incredibly appreciative to you for
putting yourself out there to start this
it's this was great and I'm really glad
that I popped on I feel like the
universe is you know trickling into
people's consciousness and somehow I
ended up here today so thank you I also
feel that this is exactly what's
supposed to happen today like the two of
us being here there was a possibility I
was gonna be sitting here all by myself
and if that happened that's possibly
what was supposed to happen but no cuz
this did and I really thank you for
reaching out and saying that you were
you were open and then coming on on this
morning so I will see everybody else
next week at 11:00 a.m. Pacific Standard
Time whenever that is your time zone for
idea cafe and I'd love to have you back
any and all times Heather all right
thanks
[Music]